Smith, Edwin S. Papers 5549
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series I. Personal Papers
  - Sub-Series C. Writings
    - History of Labor., 1962 (Box 2, Folder 1-8)
      Chapters XXXI-XXXVIII; same as above.
    - History of Labor., 1962 (Box 2, Folder 9-12)
      Bibliography
    - History of Labor., 1962 (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
      Miscellaneous draft of correspondence; discussion of automation; discussion of racial discrimination.
    - Interviews with Labor Officials and Industrialists. [folder 1 of 4], 1946-1963 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      Summaries and excerpts of interviews are arranged alphabetically and extend from one paragraph to six pages. Discussions appear to correspond to researcher subject files, and may well be related to various writing projects. Index.
      - Item 1: Interviews with Labor Officials and Industrialists., 1946-1963; Interview (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Item 2: Aaron, Benjamin (with Irving Bernstein, and Fred Myers), 1961; Interview (Box 2, Folder 15)
        11/29/1961.
      - Item 3: Abner, Willoughby, 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 15)
        6/7/1962.
      - Item 4: Allard, John F. (2nd in command of auto workers of Los Angeles area), 1961; Interview (Box 2, Folder 15)
        12/1/1961.
      - Item 5: Annand, John (Teamsters, heads S. Cal. District Council), 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 15)
        Nov- 62.
      - Item 6: Barkin, Solomon (TWUA), 1961; Interview (Box 2, Folder 15)
        11/8/1961.
      - Item 7: Block, Joseph (Division of Wages and Industrial Relations, Dept. of Labor), 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 15)
        12/23/1962.
      - Item 8: Bridges, Harry (and Goldblatt), 1961; Interview (Box 2, Folder 15)
        11/17/1961.
      - Item 9: Cantfil, William (Ass't Dir. Labor Management Reports), 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 15)
        1/28/1962.
      - Item 10: Chennault, ... (in charge of Compliance and Enforcement), 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Item 11: Daugherty, James (S. Cal. Rep. for Mine, Mill), 1961; Interview (Box 2, Folder 15)
        Dec-61.
      - Item 12: De Lacy, Hugh, 1961; Interview (Box 2, Folder 15)
        11/30/1961.
      - Item 13: Denise, ... (Vice-President of Ford Co. in charge of Labor Relations) (3/27/62), 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Item 14: Doherty, William C. Jr. (Director, Social Projects Department, The American Institute for Free Labor Development), 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 15)
        11/13/1962.
      - Item 15: Donner, Frank, 1961; Interview (Box 2, Folder 15)
        10/30/1961.
      - Item 16: Erikila, Reino (President, ILWU, Local 10, San Francisco), 1961; Interview (Box 2, Folder 15)
        11/20/1961.
      - Item 17: Fairley, Lincoln (and Sidney Rogers), 1961; Interview (Box 2, Folder 15)
        11/17/61,11/23/61.
      - Item 18: Fitzgerald, ..., 1946-1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 15)
        c.1946, 4/4/62.
    - Interviews with Labor Officials and Industrialists. [folder 2 of 4], 1946-1963 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Item 1: Flaxner, Abe, 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 16)
        1/22/1962.
      - Item 2: Fowler. C.D., 1963; Interview (Box 2, Folder 16)
        7/21/1963.
      - Item 3: Goldblatt, Lou, 1961; Interview (Box 2, Folder 16)
        12/7/1961.
      - Item 4: Golden, Ben, 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 16)
        2/27/1962.
      - Item 5: Goldenthal, ... (European Common Market Development Corp.), Interview (Box 2, Folder 16)
        n.d.
      - Item 6: Goodman, Ernie (and Philo), 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 16)
        3/27/1962.
      - Item 7: Grace, W.R., Interview (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Item 8: Hackler, Charles (formerly of NLRB, now lawyer for Teamsters Council of S. Cal.), 1961; Interview (Box 2, Folder 16)
        11/28/1961.
      - Item 9: Haessler, Carl (auto history), Interview (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Item 10: Helstein, Ralph (President, UPWA), 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 16)
        6/6/1962.
      - Item 11: Hogue, Jo (Office Manager, Local 600, UAW), Interview (Box 2, Folder 16)
        no date.
      - Item 12: Holmes, ... (Head of Teamster local, Detroit), Interview (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Item 13: Huberman, Leo (and Paul Sweezy), 1961; Interview (Box 2, Folder 16)
        10/18/1961.
      - Item 14: Johnson, Clyde (et al), 1961; Interview (Box 2, Folder 16)
        11/22/1961.
      - Item 15: Karman, Marc (Educational Director, Amalgamated), 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 16)
        8/13/1962.
      - Item 16: Kandal, Harry (UAW Diesel Plant), 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Item 17: Kenny, Robert, 1961; Interview (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Item 18: Kiestler, Alan (Organizing Dept., AFL-CIO), 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 16)
        1/29/1962.
      - Item 19: Lens, Sidney, 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Item 20: Lonergan, Edward M. (Ass't to Thomas Holleran, Trade Union Programs Division, Office of International Labor Affairs, U.S. Dept. of Labor), 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Item 21: Lyndon, Richard (Sec'y Treas. Local 6, Warehouse ILWU), Interview (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Item 22: Matles, Jim, 1961-1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 16)
        10/31/61, 2/28/62.
    - Interviews with Labor Officials and Industrialists. [folder 3 of 4], 1946-1963 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Item 1: Matles, Jim, 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 17)
        3/13/1962.
      - Item 2: Mazey, Ernie, 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 17)
        3/28/1962.
      - Item 3: Mc Elwain, Irwin (N.Y. Reg. Dir. NLRB) (n.d.), Interview (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Item 4: McTernan, Frank (Lawyer for Amalgamated Lithographers of America), 1961; Interview (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Item 5: Mills, Saul (AFL-CIO), 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 17)
        1/23/1962.
      - Item 6: Myers, Blackie, 1961; Interview (Box 2, Folder 17)
        11/18/61, 12/61.
      - Item 7: Natrella, Vito (Ass't Commissioner for Reports, Securities and Exchange Commission), 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Item 8: Nixon, Russ, 1961; Interview (Box 2, Folder 17)
        10/25/61, 11/6/61.
      - Item 9: Peters, Edwin, Interview (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Item 10: Pinski, Paul (and Virginia Wood), 1961; Interview (Box 2, Folder 17)
        12/8/1961.
      - Item 11: Poyer, Bruce (Research Director, Western Conference of Teamsters), 1961; Interview (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Item 12: Prosten, Jessie, 1972; Interview (Box 2, Folder 17)
        6/7/1972.
      - Item 13: Queen, Henry A. (Head of Investigators, Bureau of Labor Standards), 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Item 14: Randolph, A. Philip, 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 17)
        2/13/1962.
      - Item 15: Ross (interview with assistant of Ross in International Division, AFL-CIO), 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 17)
        1/30/1962.
      - Item 16: Rowell, Ed (Head of Labor Attache Program, State Dept.), 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Interviews with Labor Officials and Industrialists. [folder 4 of 4], 1946-1963 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Item 1: Sacharoff, Norris (Chief for Operations of the Labor Standards Bureau), 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Item 2: Seaton, (et al at GM in Detroit), 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 18)
        3/26/1962.
      - Item 3: Selly, Joe (and Jeff Kyber and ... Bender), Interview (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Item 4: (10/18/61, 1/8/63), 1961-1963; Interview (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Item 5: Schmidt, Henry, 1961; Interview (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Item 6: Senter, William (Letter to the editor of WFTU fortnightly paper), 1951; Interview (Box 2, Folder 18)
        12/5/1951.
      - Item 7: Shelton, ... (Division of Foreign Labor Conditions of the Labor Statistics Division of the Labor Department), 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 18)
        11/9/1962.
      - Item 8: Skolnick, ... (Dept. of Health, Education and Welfare), 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Item 9: Sturmthal, Adolph (Prof. of Economics, Bard College.), 1948; Interview (Box 2, Folder 18)
        Industrial and Labor Relations Review, vol. I, pp. 624-638, July 1948.
      - Item 10: Taylor, James (Liason man between Labor and State Departments), 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Item 11: Watts, Daniel (Liberation Committee for Africa), 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 18)
        7/3/1962.
      - Item 12: Weinberg, Nat (UAW), 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Item 13: West, ... (Assistant to Mr. Warnat of the Statistic Div. of the Labor Department), 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 18)
        11/14/1962.
      - Item 14: Witt, Nat, 1962; Interview (Box 2, Folder 18)
        5/3/62, 5/17/62, 7/10/62.
    - Poetry, 1920-1960 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Item 1: The Worker, 1960; Poem (Box 2, Folder 19)
        1/10/1960.
      - Item 2: Walkers on the Beach, 1920; Poem (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Item 3: The Lovers, 1920; Poem (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Item 4: Rejected, 1920; Poem (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Item 5: A Survivor, 1920; Poem (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Item 6: The Young Poet, 1920; Poem (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Item 7: Over the Tea Cups, 1929; Poem (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Item 8: The End, 1930; Poem (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Item 9: Unemployment, 1930; Poem (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Item 10: On Seeing Prints by Hokusai, 1929, 1930; Poem (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Item 11: To My Father: who died after a long illness, 1930; Poem (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Item 12: Hospital Flowers, 1930; Poem (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Item 13: To Dick Shaw, 1930; Poem (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Item 14: A Chaplet of Haiku, 1960; Poem (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Item 15: Life of the Humming Bird, 1960; Poem (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Item 16: Hospital, 1960; Poem (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Item 17: Viet Nam, 1960; Poem (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Item 18: Little Marion, 1960; Poem (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Item 19: Diana, 1960; Poem (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Item 20: Spring Campaign, 1960; Poem (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Proposal for a Study of Progressive Labor Unions (Box 2, Folder 20)
      no date
    - Soviet Union Trip., 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 21-25)
      Articles entitled "Trip to the Soviet Union" (9/45) and "Visit to Tolstoy Estate" (10/45); diaries and general notes (6/10/45-8/20/45) record detailed impressions of individuals, places and events (90+pp). Pamphlet (47p.) "Organized Labor in the Soviet Union." (1943)
    - "The Problem of the Workless Child" Boys' Work Exchange (11/17/33); "What Workers and Employers Should Know About the National Labor Relations Act" reprint from Labor Information Bulletin (6/37)., 1933-1937 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Sub-Series D. Miscellaneous
    - Biographical information; obituaries (1976-77); subpoena to appear before the Subcommittee on Internal Security of the Judiciary, 1953-1977 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Newspaper clippings., 1924-1976 (Box 2, Folder 28-30c)
      Includes "Scrapbook of Newspaper Clippings" which document Smith's career as Massachusetts Commissioner of Labor and Industries, and as Executive Member of the National Labor Relations Board. Many of the later clippings relate to the Senate Internal Security Subcommittee's investigation of Smith and others.
    - Photographs (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Research Notes (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Writings. Fragments of writings; tribute to Mary Bachelder Smith (Edwin Smith's aunt). (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Series II. Research Files
  - AFL-CIO General, 1961-1968 (Box 2, Folder 34-41)
  - African-Asian Conference, 1964-1967 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - AID, 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Agriculture and Agricultural Labor, 1962-1967 (Box 2, Folder 4445)
  - Alliance for Progress, 1962-1966 (Box 2, Folder 46-48)
  - Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, 1962-1966 (Box 2, Folder 49-52)
  - American Institute for Free Labor Development, 1960-1966 (Box 2, Folder 53-55)
  - Anti-Labor Propaganda - Bills and Laws, 1962-1966 (Box 2, Folder 56-58)
  - Arbitration, 1963-1967 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Asia, 1963-1967 (Box 2, Folder 60-63)
  - Automation, 1948-1965 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Automation, 1955-1964 (Box 3, Folder 1-5)
  - Black Civil Rights Movement, 1962-1967 (Box 3, Folder 6-9)
  - British Trade Unions (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Books, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 11-23)
  - Budget, 1964-1966 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Business Cycle and Business, 1961-1966 (Box 3, Folder 14-19)
  - Canada. Benjamin Caplan's "Memorandum on the Canadian Industrial Disputes Investigation Act." (Box 3, Folder 20-21)
  - Catholic Action (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Catholic Church, 1960-1964 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - CIA, 1961-1967 (Box 3, Folder 24-28)
  - Central Treaty Organization (CENTO), 1963 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - China, 1963-1966 (Box 3, Folder 30-31)
  - Christian International, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Civil Liberties, 1958-1966 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Cold War, 1962-1969 (Box 3, Folder 34-37)
  - Collective Bargaining, 1959-1966 (Box 3, Folder 38-45)
  - Comic Strip "Frontiers of Science", 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Common Market - Agriculture, 1962-1965 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Common Market, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 48-61)
  - Common Market, 1960-1963 (Box 4, Folder 1-14)
  - Common Market - Tariff, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Community Services, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Corruption, 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 17-20)
  - Cuba, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Cuban Refugees, 1960-1966 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Czechoslovakia, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 23-24)
  - Debs, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Defense, 1964-1967 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - DeMaio, Ernest, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Depreciation, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Developing Countries, 1959-1965 (Box 4, Folder 29-33)
  - Disarmament, 1961-1965 (Box 4, Folder 34-35)
  - Discrimination, 1959-1967 (Box 4, Folder 36-58)
  - Donner, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Economic Growth, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Egypt, 1962-1965 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Europe, 1963-1967 (Box 5, Folder 4-8)
  - European Coal and Steel Industry, 1963-1966 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - European Free Trade Association (EFTA), 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - European Trade Union Comm., 1961-1965 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - FBI, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Foreign Aid, 1962-1967 (Box 5, Folder 13-16)
  - Foreign Aid (Labor), 1963-1966 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Foreign Labor, 1962-1967 (Box 5, Folder 18-23)
  - Foreign Policy, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 24-25)
  - Foreign Trade, 1964-1966 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - General Motors, 1964-1966 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Germany, 1962-1970 (Box 5, Folder 28-35)
  - Germany (Box 5, Folder 36-38)
    Benjamin Caplan's "Memorandum on Labor Courts with Special Reference to the German System" and "Memorandum on the German Postwar System of Arbitration."
  - Gompers and Lincoln, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Government and Foreign Labor, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Government Aid to Business, 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - History, 1960-1968 (Box 5, Folder 42-45)
  - Histradrut, 1960-1963 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Hoffa Career - Corruption, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Holland, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Hunger, 1962-1966 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Imperialism (modern), 1966 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Income, 1961-1966 (Box 5, Folder 51-52)
  - International Bank, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - International Banking, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - International Confederation of Free Trade Unions (ICFTU), 1962-1965 (Box 5, Folder 56-59)
  - International Federation of Plantation, Agricultural and Allied Workers (IFPAAW), 1963 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - International Labor Organization (ILO), 1962-1966 (Box 5, Folder 61-62)
  - International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union (ILWU), 1962-1967 (Box 5, Folder 63-66)
  - International Monetary Fund, 1963-1965 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - International Trade and Development Corporation, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Internationals 1st and 2nd, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Industrial Workers of the World (IWW), 1963-1965 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Japan, 1962-1968 (Box 5, Folder 71-77)
  - Japan, 1963-1966 (Box 6, Folder 1-6)
  - Johnson, Lyndon Baines, 1964-1967 (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
  - Labor and Safety - Labor Attaches and Labor Dept. in Foreign Relations, 1960-1963 (Box 6, Folder 9-10)
  - Labor Dept. (U.S.), 1960-1967 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Labor-Management Committee, 1962-1965 (Box 6, Folder 12-13)
  - Labor-Management Cooperation, 1961-1964 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Labor Visitors, 1962-1964 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Landrum-Griffin Act, 1960-1965 (Box 6, Folder 16-17)
  - Latin America, 1961-1968 (Box 6, Folder 18-53)
  - Latin America, 1961-1967 (Box 7, Folder 1-16)
  - Lenin, 1917-1970 (Box 7, Folder 17-21)
  - Lewis, John L., 1963 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Lie Detectors, etc., 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Magdott (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Malaysia, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - May Day, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - McCarran Act, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - McNamara, Robert, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Meany, George, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 29-33)
  - Middle East, 1963-1967 (Box 7, Folder 34-35)
  - Migration in Europe, Migration of Industry, 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Millionaires, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Miscellany, 1950-1970 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Myrdal, Gunnar B., 1963 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - National Association of Manufacturers (NAM) and Committee for Economic Development (CED), 1962-1963 (Box 7, Folder 40-41)
  - Neo-Colonialism, 1963-1966 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Non-Aligned Nations, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO), 1964 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD), 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Organization of American States (OAS), 1965 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Overseas Investment, 1962-1968 (Box 7, Folder 47-58)
  - Peace, 1961-1965 (Box 7, Folder 59-60)
  - Plant Removal, 1962-1966 (Box 7, Folder 61-62)
  - Population, 1961-1965 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Profit, 1962-1966 (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
  - Profit Sharing, 1962-1964 (Box 8, Folder 4-5)
  - Profit-Wages, 1964-1967 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Progressive Party, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Public Ownership, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Public Works, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Raiding, 1961-1962 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Red Baiting, 1962-1964 (Box 8, Folder 11-12)
  - Right to Work, 1961-1965 (Box 8, Folder 13-15)
  - Rightists, 1961-1963 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Santo Domingo, 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 17-19)
  - Savings, 1964-1969 (Box 8, Folder 20-21)
  - Scientific Management, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Sino-Soviet Quarrel, 1963-1965 (Box 8, Folder 23-24)
  - Sites Picketing, 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Slavery, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Social Security, 1964-1967 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Socialists, 1963-1966 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Stock Ownership, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Thirty Hour Work Week, 1963-1965 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Times (New York) News Summary, 1963-1965 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Triple Revolution, 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Undercover Agencies, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Unions - Finances, 1962-1965 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Unions - Foreign Policy AFL-CIO, 1965-1967 (Box 8, Folder 35-36)
  - Unions - General, 1964-1968 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Unions - Membership, 1961-1966 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Unions - Politics, 1961-1966 (Box 8, Folder 39-41)
  - Unions - Thirty Hour Week, 1961-1964 (Box 8, Folder 42-47)
  - United Nations, 1963-1965 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - United Nations Trade and Development Conference, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - USSR, 1947-1969 (Box 8, Folder 50-56)
  - Vietnam, 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 57-62)
  - Vietnam, 1965-1969 (Box 9, Folder 1-6)
  - Vietnam - Labor, 1966-1972 (Box 9, Folder 7-8)
  - Wages and Wage Methods, 1962-1967 (Box 9, Folder 10-15)
  - Western Europe, 1963-1965 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Western European Unions, 1963-1965 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - World Bank, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - World Federation of Trade Unions (WFTU), 1961-1963 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - World Trade Conference, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - World Trade Union Unity, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 21)
- Series III. History of the National Labor Relations Board
  - Printed materials of the NLRB (Box 10, Folder 1-42)
    Includes: executive orders, resolutions, statement of powers and jurisdiction, legal memoranda, legislative history of the NLRA, concurring opinions, decisions and dissents by Edwin Smith, rules and regulations, statements of procedure, and J.M. Landis' supplement to Cases on Labor Law, entitled Labor Law.
- Series IV. Additional Papers 1932-1971
  - Sub-Series A. Correspondence
    - Correspondence., 1945-1974 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      Braden, Mrs. Anne - correspondence re articles in Monthly Review re Mississippi Freedom Labor Union; Curtiss, Marion - personal; Duryea, Perry B., Jr., House Speaker - routine; Freeman, Harry - personal re Smith's trip to Soviet Union; Ginsburg, Herman R. - personal; Gronouski, John A. - routine to Postmaster General; Huberman, Leonard - personal; Johnson, Pres. Lyndon B. - re Vietnam War; Kennedy, Robert F. - re bill restricting foreign travel; Lewis, Dr. John - routine including Smith's article "A Reply To Cornforth on Cauldwell" (21 p.); Madden, Judge J. Warren - personal; Murdock, Rep. Abe - routine; Morris, Carlyle - personal; Pike, Rep. Otis - re foreign travel restrictions, re Vietnam War (c.c. Robert F. Kennedy and Jocab Javits); Rabinowitz - Louis Rabinowitz Foundation re proposal for grant to study American trade union movement; Roosevelt, Pres. Franklin D. - card invitation; Shanahan, Paul R. - correspondence with Kansas Secretary of State; Smith, Marion & Diana - personal to wife and daughter re Smith's Soviet Union trip (1945); Soyer, Moses - personal; Stowe, Helen - personal; Times - correspondence to editor re dispute mediation; Wallace, Mrs. Harry (Anne) - personal; Woods, Dorothy - personal; Miscellaneous personal correspondence - no full names.
  - Sub-Series B. Subject Files
    - American Committee for Armenian Rights. Routine Correspondence, pamphlets, photographs., 1945-1950 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - American Economics Association Essay. Industry - A Problem in Human Resources, 1946-1950 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Under pseudonym Frederick Adams - written shortly after college graduation.
    - Berkshire Knitting Mills Strike (NLRB)., 1932-1941 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      Correspondence with American Federation of Hosiery Workers; news releases; pamphlets; "Chaos vs. Order in the Hosiery Industry" - radio address by Pres. Emil Rieve.
    - Federal Bureau of Investigations Deposition and Correspondence., 1941-1971 (Box 11, Folder 5-6)
      Correspondence with Madden, Millis, Nathan Witt.
    - Mexico City Conference - Federation of Latin American Workers., 1938-1946 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      Newspaper clippings re Pres. Cardenas; editorial "Encouragement for Cardenas"; "Red Labor Marches in Mexico" by Hartley W. Barclay; "Mexico, Our Good Red Neighbor" by Hartley W. Barclay; "America's Future - Mill and Factory"
    - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship., 1943-1945 (Box 11, Folder 8-9)
      Speeches and radio addresses including "American-Soviet Friendship for Peace and Economic Stability"; "American Labor's Stake in Allied Labor Unity"; "Importance of Friendship with the Soviet Union"
    - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship., 1943-1945 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      Scrapbook contents including photographs, newspaper clippings, and pamphlets.
    - Oil Workers Organizing Campaign., 1943-1978 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      Correspondence with Clyde Johnson re book on subject; routine correspondence; photographs.
    - Parish Art Museum., 1968 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      Routine correspondence, petitions, newspaper clippings re dismissal of George Perret as Museum Director.
    - Poland Business Proposals., 1945-1947 (Box 11, Folder 13)